nmnknwr@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/namankanwar/ +1-470-263-0059 naman26.github.io

Professional Summary

5+ years of experience in software engineering, data engineering, and machine learning. Extensive experience in working with multi-disciplinary teams, establishing and supporting ETL pipelines for Walmart and LexisNexis Risk. Seeking opportunities to leverage data skills in a collaborative environment.

Education

Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA

Master of Science in Computer Science Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Aug 2019 — Jul 2020 Jun 2016 — Jul 2019

Skills

- Languages: Python (Proficient), Java, SQL
- Database and Frameworks: Google Cloud Platform (Big Query, Dataproc, GCS, Dataflow, VMs), Azure (Databricks, Blob storage), Airflow, Pyspark, AWS Lambda, Amazon (QuickSight, SageMaker, S3), MariaDB
- · Concepts: Object-Oriented Programming, Agile/Scrum, Multithreading, ETL, Data Analysis, Data Mining, Big Data
- Other: Spring Boot, Linux, Git, Jenkins, Docker, JFrog, Flask, Selenium

Experience

Walmart Atlanta, GA

Walmart Global Tech - Data Engineer III

August 2022 – Present

- Orchestrated, developed, and maintained 20+ batch/streaming ETL pipelines (Airflow).
- o Integrated service now requests tickets with existing CI/CD process saving over 10 manual hours per deployment.
- o Followed industry standard and improved code coverage of major repositories to 95% (SonarQube)
- Onboarded a new project creating batch data pipelines with SCD tables (Airflow, Dataproc, Google Dataflow, Pyspark, BigQuery, and GCS).
- o Migrated legacy Automic pipelines to Airflow with 100% code coverage (Pyspark, GCP, Databricks, and Azure).
- Automated CI/CD flow to drain and create new dataflow jobs saving manual effort of 1-2 sprints per pom.xml update (Jenkins, Docker and Maven).
- Implemented and maintained proper security standards for all data pipelines end to end ensuring 0% data loss (Google Secret Manager).
- Optimized cloud cost by fine-tuning clusters and worker nodes saving over \$100K annually (Azure and GCP).
- o Contributed to internal artifactory with 70+ downloads across the division (JFrog).
- o Improved a REST API dag's performance by reducing 90% of cloud compute time (Dataproc, Pyspark).
- Mitigated on-call failures in pipelines and supported expected outages by providing clients with data within the 1st hour of failure.

LexisNexis Risk Solutions Alpharetta, GA

LNRS - Software Engineer II

February 2021 – August 2022

- Developed search functionality and an interface for clients to find matches within 2s from entire database.
- Using ETL process, implemented phonetic and fuzzy matching to reduce search time by 5ms.
- Analyzed data usage and optimized databases to reduce storage cost for cloud migration.
- o Created and evaluated crosswalk interfaces based on precision and recall.
- Worked with different environments, coordinated merges and code releases using git, CI/CD (Git lab) and SQL Server
- Created and automated a testing system by utilizing CRON jobs saving 120 work hours.
- Met client expectations by generating B2C and C2B reports of data sets containing 30,000,000+ records, in a timely manner.

Georgia State EBCS Atlanta, GA

Evidence Based Cyber Security Group - Data Engineer

Aug 2019 - Aug 2020

- Developed web scrapers to collect data from suspicious websites. Engineered CAPTCHA breaking system with 90% accuracy rate to automate the scrapers.
- Created automatic weekly business report, empowering institute-wide policy decisions using Python, Selenium, SQL and folium.
- Coordinated with the associate director to maintain and develop EBCS website (ebcs.gsu.edu). Onboarded and handed project to incoming developer.

Fiserv Atlanta, GA

Global Finance Solution - Software Development Engineer Intern

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Worked on 35,000+ lines of C++ code with no existing documentation. Wrote documentation for existing and newly added code.
- o Automated database server shutdown and creation, saving 12% annual costs.

Georgia State CS Department

Atlanta, GA

Computer Science Department - Data Engineer

Oct 2017 – Aug 2019

- Implemented an algorithm that visualizes evolutionary trees using Python. Reduced the execution time of current algorithm by 99%.
- o Designed an API along with a full stack website architecture to deploy the algorithm.
- Integrated interactive visualization of data using D3.js. Completed and deployed the website within 4 months which
 is being used by hundreds of biologists.

Verizon Connect Atlanta, GA

Fleetmatics - Data Analyst

Jun 2017 – Aug 2017

- o Directly increased userbase by 20% utilizing data mining techniques for analysis.
- o Built analytics dashboards from Hive tables using Java to depict user driving behavior.
- Utilized Apache Spark to develop data analytics for business intelligence and product development.

Certifications

• AWS Fundamentals Specialization Credentials: https://coursera.org/share/fd170135c42c76a2015a0d961a6edbdf
Coursera Oct 2020

Java Developer Credentials: hackerrank.com/certificates/4f83321244ab

HackerRank Aug 2020

Python Developer Credentials: hackerrank.com/certificates/540a2bdaaf11

HackerRank Aug 2020

Other

Awards

4+ National Hackathon Awards

- o HackGT: 2019: Optical Character Challenge Runner-Up
- o HackGSU: 2019: 1st in Crypto challenge, 2017: Anthem Grand Prize
- o HackATL: 2018: Health and Wellness Challenge Runner-Up
- o Georgia State University: 2018: Outstanding Undergraduate Research Award